Ernesto Nolasco

Site Reliability Engineer

Profile

Experienced IT professional with a diverse set of skills spanning network administration, VMware infrastructure, and basic knowledge of DevOps.

Experience in virtualization technologies implementing, managing and monitoring VMware clusters, ensuring high availability and scalability. Network administration, configuring and maintaining server infrastructure based on Linux and Windows, as well as solving complex network problems and responding to security incidents.

DevOps enthusiast with basic knowledge of continuous integration and continuous deployment using tools such as Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible, Terraform AWS and Azure.

In addition to technical experience, I possess the ability to manage multiple tasks and priorities effectively, a strong set of soft communication skills with a collaborative approach, creativity, adaptability and flexibility when facing new challenges.

Dedicated to continuous learning and self-improvement to continually expand my knowledge and skills.

Details

Havana, Cuba +5353200037 ernesto.nolasco@gmail.com

Skills

Network administration Basic DevOps Basic Pentesting VMware Esxi Proxmox

Languages

Spanish- Native Speaker **English**- Advanced

LinkedIn: ernesto-nolasco

Work Experience

Site Reliability Engineer at CITMAtel. Cuba

Sept. 2021 - present

- Implementation and deployment of a SIEM using Suricata and ELK.
- Deployment and configuration of a Kubernetes cluster on premises
- Cluster installation and administration using Docker Swarm as development environment.
- Deployment, configuration and administration of Gitlab server on premises.
- Docker integration with Gitlab using Gitlab pipelines and runners on premises.
- Integration of Ansible Semaphore with Gitlab as an alternative to Ansible Tower on premises.
- Containerization of FIWARE IoT infrastructure using Docker.
- Installation and configuration of infrastructure for continuous integration on premises.
- Security testing automation using Ansible with Nmap and OpenVas.
- Virtualization of network services using HA clusters with Esxi in production environments.
- Incident responses in production HA clusters powered by VMware.
- Virtualization of network services using Proxmox clusters.
- Analysis and correction of vulnerabilities in corporate networks and IoT devices.
- Installation and configuration of data storage servers for small clusters.
- Monitoring and administration of data centers.

Technologies used: Esxi, Proxmox VE, IaC, Gitlab Pipelines, Git, Gitlab, Docker, Nexus Sonatype3, Portainer, Ansible, Terraform, Kubernetes, SIEM, ELK, Terraform, Zabbix, Nmap, OpenVAS, Wireshark.

Network Manager, IT Security, IT Services Principal at Cuban Marble Company. Cuba

Mar 2018 - Jul 2021

- Principal on IT Network and Security.
- SMA inverter cluster network configuration for solar panels control.
- Management of corporate antivirus servers.
- Installation and configuration of computer network advanced services.
- Penetration testing to network infrastructure and remove vulnerabilities.
- Support to automation machinery marble team.
- Python programming course.

Technologies used: Esxi 6.5, PFSense, Linux, SMA solar inverters, Windows Server 2016, PowerCLI, Python, Kaspersky, Kali Linux, Veeam Backup.

Network Manager, IT Security, IT Services Manager at Nuclear Energy Agency and Advanced Technologies. Cuba

Feb. 2014 - Mar. 2018

- Responsible for leading a team of specialists on IT Network and Security.
- CITMA advisory Cybersecurity group.
- IAEA international Project (RLA0046 Coordinated strengthening of communication in the ARCAL countries and strategic associations to promote nuclear applications and their sustainability in Latin America).
- IT focal point for the IAEA-ARCAL Communication platform.
- Third Introductory Regional Course of Use the E-Learning tools as a support for the nuclear education and capacitation.
- GECYT Adjunct Consultant.
- Install and development of a private cloud using Owncloud.
- Installation of Wi-Fi technology
- Backups of network infrastructure.
- Website programming using CMS.
- Wireless networks course

Technologies used Parrot OS, WordPress, SharePoint 2013, Veeam Backup, Access Point, SQL server, Owncloud, Moodle, Openfiler, ESXI 5.5, Forefront TMG, Centos.

Network Manager, IT Security, Software Developer, Technical Support Supervisor at Center for Information Management and Energy Development. Cuba

Sep. 2006 - Jan. 2014

- Assembly of computer networks.
- Supervision of Advanced Technical Support.
- Grid computing support and administration team.
- Infrastructure support in EELA International Project
- Migration of network services, from proprietary software to free software.
- Administration of the Cuban INIS Data Center.
- Programming of the Cuba Catalog INIS NCL Online
- Project "Demonstrative grid connection photovoltaic system".

Technologies used: MySQL, PHP, CSS, HTML, MARC21 Bibliographic Format, Grid Computer Site, Moodle.

Other Projects

Web site for Cubasolar ONG

Technologies used: PHP, HTML, CSS, WordPress.

Education

1998-2003 Licentiate in Electrical, Superior Institute for Education Technical and Professional, Havana.